<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./PredictorView.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
    <name>Predictor View JS (deprecated)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        The model plotter plots the first PMM model available in the input data table in a
        JavaScript view.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        This is the deprecated implementation of the Prediector View JS node. It is no longer supported.
        
        The model plotter plots the first PMM model available in the input data table in a
        JavaScript view. If more plotable functions are provided in the input table only the
        first will be plottet and a warning will be shown. 
        
        All variables (arguments) of the plotable function can be adjusted in the view by
        sliders. Values of constants will be taken from the PMM input and can be changed in the
        view as well. 
        </intro>
        <option name="Chart title">
            The chart title will be shown as headline right above the plot. 
        </option>
        <option name="Y0 (log10(count/g))">
            Value of constant Y0 with unit log10(count/g).  
        </option>
        <option name="Min x-axis">
            The minimum value of the x axis.   
        </option>
        <option name="Max x-axis">
            The maximum value of the x axis.   
        </option>
        <option name="Min y-axis">
            The minimum value of the y axis.   
        </option>
        <option name="Max y-axis">
            The maximum value of the y axis.   
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <interactiveView name="Model Plotter">
        The view plots the function of the first model.
    </interactiveView>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Fitted models">
            Fitted primary or secondary models and parameters (e.g. from the nodes Model Fitting, 
            Model Reader, XLS Model Reader, Model Creator)
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Model constants">
            Constant names and values used in the model function. Values are shown and can be 
            changed in the view.
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Model variables">
            Variable names and values used in the model function. Values are shown and can be 
            changed in the view.
        </outPort>
    </ports>    

</knimeNode>
