<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="FSKEnvironmentCreator.png" type="Sink" deprecated="false"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>FSKX Environment Creator</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Creates and configures a Conda environment for FSKX modeling and propagates it to downstream nodes.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node creates a customizable Conda environment, designed for use in workflows involving FSKX models, and allows the environment to be propagated to downstream nodes that are Conda-aware. This enables users to replicate the environment configuration across different machines or servers seamlessly, making workflows portable and reproducible. Key steps for using this node are:
			<ol>
				<li>Ensure Conda is installed and properly configured in the KNIME preferences. Refer to the KNIME <a href="https://docs.knime.com/latest/python_installation_guide">Python installation guide</a> for setup instructions.</li>
				<li>Configure the node by selecting a Conda environment or creating a new one. If creating a new environment, specify the language and packages required.</li>
				<li>Upon execution without a dialog opening, the node will create a Conda environment using the language specified in the previous node and assign it a name based on the pattern "conda" + the model ID. This ensures that downstream nodes can execute within the correct environment configured for the workflow.</li>			
				<li>Connect this node’s output port to Conda-aware nodes downstream using a flow variable port.</li>
				<li>The downstream nodes, will use the propagated Conda environment.</li>
			</ol>
		</intro>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Conda environment" index="0">
			Optional flow variable to get LanguageWrittenIn and packages needed to be installed in the proposed Conda1 environment.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Conda environment" index="0">
			Flow variable pointing to the created or configured Conda environment.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
