<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  PMM-Lab © 2012-2014, Federal Institute for Risk Assessment (BfR), Germany
  
  PMM-Lab is a set of KNIME-Nodes and KNIME workflows running within the KNIME software plattform (http://www.knime.org.).
  
  PMM-Lab © 2012-2014, Federal Institute for Risk Assessment (BfR), Germany
  Contact: armin.weiser@bfr.bund.de or matthias.filter@bfr.bund.de 
  
  Developers and contributors to the PMM-Lab project are 
  Christian Thöns (BfR)
  Matthias Filter (BfR)
  Armin A. Weiser (BfR)
  Alexander Falenski (BfR)
  Jörgen Brandt (BfR)
  Annemarie Käsbohrer (BfR)
  Bernd Appel (BfR)
  
  PMM-Lab is a project under development. Contributions are welcome.
  
  
  This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
  it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
  the Free Software Foundation, either version 3 of the License, or
  (at your option) any later version.
  
  This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
  but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
  MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
  GNU General Public License for more details.
  
  You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
  along with this program.  If not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses/>.
-->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./ModelCreator.png" type="Source">
    <name>Model Creator</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Enter estimated primary and secondary models
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Enter primary and / or secondary models. In contrast to the Formula Creator, not only a mathematical formula can be entered but also parameter values (column 'value') and environmental conditions (tab 'Microbial Data'). This node is useful to enter fitted models, for example from the literature.</intro>
        
        <option name="MODEL DEFINITION"></option>
        <option name="Model type">Define type of model: Primary, secondary or primary (secondary). The latter is a combination of one primary and one or more secondary models.</option>
        <option name="Formula from DB">Choose one of the formulas from the internal database if the aim is to create a variation of a stored formula. To enter a completely new formula do not change this field.</option>
        <option name="Formula name">Enter a name for the new formula.</option>
        <option name="Type">Choose the type of the model (e.g. inactivation in case of a primary model or T if a secondary model models the change of a parameter depending on the temperature.</option>
        <option name="Formula">Enter the formula and click 'Apply'. Enter e.g. '2x' as '2*x', if '2' does not belong to the parameter name. Brackets may not be used left of the equals sign: "N(t) = a*(b+c)" -> "N = a*(b+c)".</option>
        <option name="Parameter Definition">Define the independent parameter. If known, also enter value, standard error, minimum and maximum values for the parameter. If the option 'primary (secondary)' was chosen click on a parameter name in order to define the secondary model for this parameter.</option>
        <option name="Model Name">Enter an informative name, e.g. 'E coli in culture medium at 30 C.</option>
        <option name="Goodness of fit">If known from a previously estimated model (e.g. from the literature), enter values for R<sup>2</sup>, root mean square (RMS), Akaike information criterion (AIC) or Bayesian information criterion (BIC).</option>
        <option name="References">Click 'New Reference', choose a reference from the internal database and click OK to link it to the formula. The new reference can be chosen from the internal database. If the reference is not yet in there click the '+' button to manually enter a new reference.</option>
        <option name="MICROBIAL DATA">Enter details about the experimental conditions leading to the data for which the entered model was estimated.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="Microbial model table">Model formula(s) with parameters, goodness of fit and additional information</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
